export const FINANCIALACCOUNTINGA2021 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The original record containing the details of a transaction which serves as a basis for posting is __________.",
A: "general ledger",
B: "source document",
C: "subsidiary book",
D: "trial balance",
answer: "B. source document",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. In the preparation of financial statements, full disclosure of minor events are ignored in line with _________.",
A: "accrual concept",
B: "money measurement concept",
C: "business entity concept",
D: "materiality concept",
answer: "B. business entity concept",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. A limitation of the money measurement concept is that _________.",
A: "it results in inaccurate statements",
B: "financial statement is not easily understood",
C: "important non-monetary activities are not reported",
D: "the reports are not comparable to that of other businesses",
answer: "C. important non-monetary activities are not reported",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Where partners maintain a fluctuating capital account, partners’ share of profit is credited to ________.",
A: "capital account",
B: "profit and loss appropriation account",
C: "current account",
D: "profit and loss account",
answer: "A. capital account",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The difference between the market value of goods produced and the cost of production is _________.",
A: "net profit on goods sold",
B: "gross profit on manufacturing",
C: "closing stock of work-in-progress",
D: "prime cost of manufacturing",
answer: "B. gross profit on manufacturing",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The residual profit of the business for the year is __________.",
A: "D47,000",
B: "D34,000",
C: "D22,000",
D: "D21,000",
answer: "D. D21,000",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Attama’s share of profit is _________.",
A: "D21,000",
B: "D19,428",
C: "D12,000",
D: "D9,000",
answer: "C. D12,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Reducing balance method charges depreciation as fixed percentage of the ___________",
A: "net book value of asset",
B: "cost of asset",
C: "market value of asset",
D: "accumulated depreciation on asset",
answer: "A. net book value of asset",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Goods returned t the supplier is recorded in the accounts as: debit",
A: "Sales Returns Account; credit Supplier’s Account.",
B: "Purchases Returns Account; credit Supplier’s Account.",
C: "Supplier’s Account; credit Purchases Returns Account.",
D: "Supplier’s Account; credit Purchases Account.",
answer: "C. Supplier’s Account; credit Purchases Returns Account.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Net profit of a sole proprietor is transferred to the _________.",
A: "profit and loss account",
B: "profit and loss appropriation account",
C: "capital account",
D: "drawings account",
answer: "C. capital account",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Accounting evolved out of the need of businesses for ________.",
A: "profit making",
B: "record keeping",
C: "increasing sales",
D: "obtaining finance",
answer: "A. profit making",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Sales account was undercast by GH¢1,000. When this is corrected, both the gross profit and the net profit would _________.",
A: "increase by GH¢2,000",
B: "increase by GH¢1,000",
C: "decrease by GH¢1,000",
D: "decrease by GH¢2,000",
answer: "B. increase by GH¢1,000",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The stock turnover period is ________.",
A: "88 days",
B: "73 days",
C: "58 days",
D: "41 days",
answer: "B. 73 days",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The mark-up is _________.",
A: "88%",
B: "80%",
C: "44.44%",
D: "26.67%",
answer: "B. 80%",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Company as a legal entity means that it ________.",
A: "must always have a company lawyer",
B: "can sue and be sued",
C: "must settle disputes among shareholders in court",
D: "should prepare accounts approved by a lawyer",
answer: "B. can sue and be sued",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The type of stock recorded in the trading account of a manufacturing business is ___________.",
A: "raw materials",
B: "work- in-progres",
C: "consumables",
D: "finished goods",
answer: "A. raw materials",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Accounts of fixed assets are kept in the ________.",
A: "purchase ledger",
B: "private ledger",
C: "sales ledger",
D: "general ledger",
answer: "D. general ledger",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Recurrent expenditure of a local government include _________.",
A: "erection of market stalls.",
B: "repayment of loans.",
C: "purchase of office equipment.",
D: "purchase of office stationery.",
answer: "D. purchase of office stationery.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The accounting principle of double entry states that _________.",
A: "debit the giver and credit the receiver.",
B: "assets must be equal to capital plus liabilities.",
C: "every debit entry must have a corresponding credit entry.",
D: "debit entries increase liabilities while credit entries increase assets.",
answer: "C. every debit entry must have a corresponding credit entry.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Lima paid off debt of D2,500 owed to Dongo by cash. The entries in Lima’s books are: debit.",
A: "cash D2,500; credit Dongo D2,500.",
B: "Dongo D2,500; credit cash D2,500.",
C: "Bad Debt D2,500; credit Dongo D2,500.",
D: "Dongo D2,500; credit Bad Debt D2,500.",
answer: "B. Dongo D2,500; credit cash D2,500.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The petty cash account has an imprest of GH¢36,000 and a debit balance of GH¢10,000 at the end of month. The reimbursement required would be ________.",
A: "GH¢46,000",
B: "GH¢36,000",
C: "GH¢26,000",
D: "GH¢10,000",
answer: "B. GH¢36,000",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Commercial activities undertaken by a social club to raise funds include _______.",
A: "donation.",
B: "bar.",
C: "grant.",
D: "subscription.",
answer: "B. bar.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The final stage of accounting process is __________.",
A: "interpretation.",
B: "recording.",
C: "reporting.",
D: "summarizing.",
answer: "C. reporting.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The value of goods sent to a branch is debited to the _______.",
A: "Goods sent to Branch Account.",
B: "Branch Debtors Account.",
C: "Branch Adjustment Account.",
D: "Branch Stock Account.",
answer: "D. Branch Stock Account.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The major source of revenue for central/Federal government is ______.",
A: "tenement rate.",
B: "excise duty.",
C: "market toll.",
D: "parking toll.",
answer: "B. excise duty.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. A business includes 50% mark-up on all its products. This would mean margin of __________.",
A: "66 2/3%",
B: "66 1/3%",
C: "33 2/3%",
D: "33 1/3%",
answer: "D. 33 13%",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Sales for the period is __________.",
A: "GH₵ 234,400",
B: "GH₵ 210,500",
C: "GH₵ 133,600",
D: "GH₵ 76,900",
answer: "A. GH₵ 234,400",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Other operating expenses for the period is ________.",
A: "GH₵ 27,300",
B: "GH₵ 25,700",
C: "GH₵ 24,700",
D: "GH₵ 23,900",
answer: "C. GH₵ 24,700",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. All cash transactions of a not-for-profit making organization are recorded in _________.",
A: "three-column cash book.",
B: "income and expenditure account.",
C: "subscriptions account.",
D: "receipts and payments account.",
answer: "D. receipts and payments account.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Subsidiary books of account are used to record transactions ________.",
A: "made in the same period.",
B: "of a similar nature.",
C: "involving minor amounts.",
D: "without source documents.",
answer: "A. made in the same period.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Members of a not-for-profit making organization __________.",
A: "earn dividend on their contributions.",
B: "do not receive surplus at the end of the year.",
C: "are paid interest on their contributions.",
D: "share profits according to their contributions.",
answer: "B. do not receive surplus at the end of the year.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Accounting information that is useful for the intended purpose and would make a difference in decision making is ____________.",
A: "compare.",
B: "consistent.",
C: "relevant.",
D: "reliable",
answer: "D. reliable",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Manufacturing account is prepared to determine the ________.",
A: "cost of goods sold.",
B: "cost of goods produced.",
C: "profit on goods produced.",
D: "value of work-in-progress.",
answer: "B. cost of goods produced.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The concept that enables a business to determine the actual profit or loss for a particular period is ________.",
A: "accrual concept.",
B: "business entity concept.",
C: "consistency concept.",
D: "going concern concept.",
answer: "A. accrual concept.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. An amount set aside out of profit for a specific purpose is a ________.",
A: "reserve.",
B: "liability.",
C: "provision.",
D: "discount.",
answer: "A. reserve.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Payment to creditors is __________.",
A: "N1,423,000.",
B: "N1,359,000.",
C: "N1,333,000.",
D: "N1,295,000.",
answer: "B. N1,359,000.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Amount owed to creditors on 31/12/19 is _________.",
A: "₦406,000.",
B: "₦342,000.",
C: "₦316,000.",
D: "₦226,000.",
answer: "C. ₦316,000.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The objective of preparing departmental accounts is to determine the __________.",
A: "sales of each department",
B: "total cost attributed to each department",
C: "capital employed by each each department",
D: "profitability of each department",
answer: "D. profitability of each department",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The partner who partakes in the management of the firm and assumes personal responsibility for the firm’s debts is a ________.",
A: "general partner",
B: "sleeping partner",
C: "quasi partner",
D: "limited partner",
answer: "A. general partner",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Acid test ratio of a firm measures the _________.",
A: "profitability of a firm.",
B: "capital adequacy of a firm.",
C: "liquidity of a firm.",
D: "quality of a firm.",
answer: "C. liquidity of a firm.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Depreciation for the year 2019 is ________.",
A: "₦180,000",
B: "₦166,500",
C: "₦90,000",
D: "₦76,500",
answer: "D. ₦76,500",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The Net book value of the asset at 31/12/19 is _________.",
A: "₦523,500",
B: "₦510,000",
C: "₦433,500",
D: "₦420,000",
answer: "C. ₦433,500",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Wages accrued is shown in the balance sheet as __________.",
A: "an asset.",
B: "an income.",
C: "an expense.",
D: "a liability.",
answer: "A. an asset.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Provision is made in the accounts when the amount involved in the anticipated loss is __________.",
A: "too much",
B: "not significant",
C: "not certain",
D: "well known",
answer: "C. not certain",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Accounting concepts are rules of accounting which are to be ________.",
A: "taught in all accounting classes.",
B: "implemented by all professional bodies.",
C: "followed in the preparation of financial statements",
D: "applied in the correction of business errors",
answer: "C. followed in the preparation of financial statements",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Rent expense for 2018 was ________.",
A: "GH¢ 84,000.",
B: "GH¢ 48,000.",
C: "GH¢ 36,000.",
D: "GH¢ 12,000.",
answer: "C. GH¢ 36,000.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The balance of rent in the balance sheet would be _________.",
A: "current asset of GH¢ 36,000.",
B: "current asset of GH¢ 12,000.",
C: "current liability of GH¢ 12,000.",
D: "current liability of GH¢ 48,000.",
answer: "A. current asset of GH¢ 36,000.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Suspense account is used in the correction of ___________.",
A: "all errors in the trial balance.",
B: "errors that affect the agreement of a trial balance.",
C: "errors that do not affect the agreement of a trial balance.",
D: "errors that affect the accuracy of the net profit.",
answer: "B. errors that affect the agreement of a trial balance.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. A transaction that would cause the cash book balance to be less than the bank statement balance is ________.",
A: "direct debit.",
B: "standing order.",
C: "bank charges.",
D: "unpresented cheques.",
answer: "D. unpresented cheques.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The costs of goods sold for the year is Le200,000 and mark-up is 30%. The sale for the year is _________.",
A: "Le260,000",
B: "Le200,000",
C: "Le140,000",
D: "Le60,000",
answer: "A. Le260,000",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]